<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>US FWS</origin>
				<pubdate>20120105</pubdate>
				<title>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service Landscape Conservation Cooperatives</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>USA</pubplace>
					<publish>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink></onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>Landscape conservation cooperatives (LCCs) are conservation-science partnerships between the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), and other federal agencies, states, tribes, NGOs, universities and stakeholders within a geographically defined area. They inform resource management decisions to address national-scale stressors-including habitat fragmentation, genetic isolation, spread of invasive species, and water scarcity-all of which are accelerated by climate change.</abstract>
			<purpose>LCCs provide scientific and technical support for conservation at "landscape" scales-the entire range of an identified priority species or groups of species. They support biological planning, conservation design, prioritizing and coordinating research, and designing species inventory and monitoring programs. LCCs also have a role in helping partners identify common goals and priorities to target the right science in the right places for efficient and effective conservation. By functioning as network of interdependent units rather than independent entities, LCC partnerships can accomplish a conservation mission no single agency or organization can accomplish alone.</purpose>
			<supplinf>For further information go to http://www.fws.gov/science/shc/lcc.html  Collectively, LCCs will comprise a seamless national network supporting landscapes capable of sustaining abundant, diverse and healthy populations of fish, wildlife and plants. They will provide a strong link between science and conservation delivery without duplicating existing partnerships or creating burdensome and unnecessary bureaucracy.  Science-based recommendations and decision-support tools produced by LCCs will be readily transferable to field offices that implement on-the-ground actions. Rather than create a new conservation infrastructure from the ground up, LCCs build upon explicit biological management priorities and objectives, and science available from existing partnerships, such as fish habitat partnerships, migratory bird joint ventures and flyway councils, as well as species- and geographic-based partnerships.  LCCs support adaptive resource management by evaluating implementation of conservation strategies, maintaining and sharing information and data, and improving products as new information becomes available. Shared data platforms serve multiple purposes, including the collaborative development of population/habitat models under alternative climate scenarios to inform spatially explicit decision support for all partners.  Decision-support systems and products developed by LCCs not only help determine the most effective conservation actions to support shared priorities, but also provide tools to compare and contrast the implications of management alternatives.  In the face of accelerated climate change and other 21st-century conservation challenges, LCCs will regularly evaluate the effectiveness of scientific information and conservation actions and support necessary adjustments as new information becomes available. This iterative process of information sharing will help scientists and resource managers deal with uncertainties on the landscape and provide tools to compare and contrast the implications of management alternatives.    LCCs were created from Geographic Areas.  See http://www.fws.gov/science/shc/index.html for further information.  This layer was created through a union of the Bird Conservation Region (BCR) layer and the Freshwater Ecoregions layer (FEOW).  The purpose of this union was to retrieve some of the linework and attributes from the FEOW layer.  Some linework from the FEOW layer was used to split some BCRs in order to accommodate high priority aquatic areas.  It was also decided to union in the "Mid Atlantic" Hydrographic Unit Code (HUC) Region (Level 2) into this dataset so we could use the actual topographic boundary between the Mid-Atlantic Region (including the James and Chesapeake) from the South-Atlantic Gulf Region (including the Chowan-Roanoake) to split the Atlantic coast area.  This was used instead of  the FEOW boundary in this area because it diverged from the topographic boundary.  After the edits were made by the mapping sub-group, this layer had the multi-part to single-part tool run on it and all polygons that had a BCR = 0 were deleted.  These polygons were either the sliver polygons that were created where the FEOW and the BCR coast lines differed or FEOW polygons from areas not in North America.  This was done to clean up the dataset.  It also allowed the Team to select and classify the many small island polygons along the coast that were accidentally dropped out during the quick group editing process.    “Gulf Coast Prairie” was updated to extend further east, Sept. 16, 2009.    Names for several geographic areas were changed.  “Insular Pacific-Hawaii” became “Pacific Islands,”” Northern Great Plains” became “Plains and Prairie Potholes,”” Northern Rockies” became “Great Northern” to comply more closely with LCC names.  Changed Oct 7, 2009.   The Geographic Area "South Pacific" was changed to "California"; "Northern Interior Forest" was changed to "Northwestern Interior Forest" and "Northern Atlantic" was changed to "North Atlantic".  The “Pacific Islands” area was  enlarged to include the new area identified by the regional climate change group.  All edits were vetted through the FWS National Climate Team.  November 12, 2009.    Changes in geographic area names have been approved by LCC Coordinators Teresa Woods (“Eastern Tallgrass Prairie” is now “Eastern Tallgrass Prairie and Big Rivers”), Bob Ford (“South Florida” is now “Peninsular Florida”), Kathy Granillo (“Southern Great Plains” is now “Great Plains”) and Laverne Smith (“Northern Alaska” is now “Arctic”) on December 7, 2009.   "Gulf Coast Plain and Ozarks" Geographic Area/LCC name changed to "Gulf Coastal Plains and Ozarks"  (authorized by R4 Bill Uihlein - Interim Coordinator), "Arctic Plains and Mountains" Geographic Area name/LCC changed to "Arctic"  (authorized by Phillip Martin - R7 Interim Coordinator), Dec 23, 2009.    Data correction - added “Great Lakes” area to “Upper Midwest and Great Lakes” geographic area (authorized by Dan Ash (Science Advisor), John Wenburg (Acting Deputy Science Advisor) and Teresa Woods (R3 Interim LCC Coordinator)), Jan 6, 2010.    Changed “Arctic” LCC to include entire Arctic Geographic Area  (authorized by LaVerne Smith (R7 Science Applications ARD), Phillip Martin (R7 Interim LCC Coordinator), and John Wenburg (Acting Deputy Science Advisor)).  Removed “Upper Midwest and Great Lakes” LCC.    Combined Geographic Areas and LCC dataset into one layer of information and removed references to those LCCs that have FWS operational plans to make the datasets more generic and to conform to the current maps on the FWS and DOI websites (authorized by Chris Lett, John Wenburg, and David Eisenhauer, April 15, 2010.)  Caribbean LCC added December 18, 2011, compiled from United Stated Exclusive Economic Zone around Puerto Rico, approved by Doug Austen, National LCC Coordinator, on December 14, 2011. Data correction – “Northwestern Inland Forest” renamed “Northwest Boreal.”</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<current>publication date</current>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20120105</caldate>
					<time>unknown</time>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Planned</progress>
			<update>As needed</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-180.000000</westbc>
				<eastbc>180.000000</eastbc>
				<northbc>83.148084</northbc>
				<southbc>-15.422167</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>US Fish and Wildlife Service</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>National GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>755 Parfet St, Suite #250</address>
					<city>Lakewood</city>
					<state>CO</state>
					<postal>80215</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>303-275-2348</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>fwsgis@fws.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3000</native>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekey>landscape conservation cooperatives, fish and wildlife service, partnerships, conservation</themekey>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
			</theme>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>Inherent in any data set used to develop graphical representations, are limitations of accuracy as determined by, among others, the source, scale and resolution of the data. While the USFWS makes every effort to represent the data as completely and accurately as possible (given existing time and resource constraints), the USFWS gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. In addition, the USFWS shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained in. Graphical representations provided by the use of this data do not represent a legal description of any kind.</useconst>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>Not available</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>Not Available</logic>
		<complete>Not Available</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>Not Available</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
		</posacc>
		<lineage></lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf><esriterm Name="lcc"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">0</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
				<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
		<vertdef>
			<altsys>
				<altres>0.000100</altres>
				<altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
			</altsys>
		</vertdef>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="lcc">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>FWS_LCC</enttypl>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">0</enttypc></enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_names</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Name of the Landscape Conservation Cooperative</attrdef>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">area_names</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Area_Num</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Unique number for each Landscape Conservation Cooperative</attrdef>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Area_Num</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">5</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">5</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
		</detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service (USFWS), HQ, IRTM, BDSS</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos></cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service</address>
					<address>IRTM - BCT</address>
					<address>755 Parfet St. Suite #250</address>
					<city>Lakewood</city>
					<state>CO</state>
					<postal>80215</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>303-275-2348</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>fwsgis@fws.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<transize>5.089</transize>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr></networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20100415</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service (USFWS),HQ, IRTM, BDSS</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>National GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service</address>
					<address>IRTM - BCT</address>
					<address>755 Parfet St. Suite #250</address>
					<city>Lakewood</city>
					<state>Colorado</state>
					<postal>80215</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>303-275-2348</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>fwsgis@fws.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
	</metainfo>
	<timeperd>
		<timeinfo>
			<sngdate>
				<caldate>20120105</caldate>
			</sngdate>
		</timeinfo>
		<current>publication date</current>
	</timeperd>
	<status>
		<progress>In work</progress>
		<update>As needed</update>
	</status>
	<spdom>
		<bounding>
			<westbc>-179.957070</westbc>
			<eastbc>-52.543750</eastbc>
			<northbc>83.148084</northbc>
			<southbc>14.544255</southbc>
		</bounding>
	</spdom>
	<keywords>
		<theme>
			<themekt>None</themekt>
			<themekey>Geographic</themekey>
			<themekey>Fish and Wildlife Service</themekey>
			<themekey>FWS</themekey>
		</theme>
		<place>
			<placekt>None</placekt>
			<placekey>USA</placekey>
		</place>
	</keywords>
	<accconst>None</accconst>
	<useconst>Inherent in any data set used to develop graphical representations, are limitations of accuracy as determined by, among others, the source, scale and resolution of the data. While the USFWS makes every effort to represent the data as completely and accurately as possible (given existing time and resource constraints), the USFWS gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. In addition, the USFWS shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained in. Graphical representations provided by the use of this data do not represent a legal description of any kind.</useconst>
	<ptcontac>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntorgp>
				<cntorg>US Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS), R9, IRTM, BDSS</cntorg>
			</cntorgp>
			<cntpos></cntpos>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
				<address>U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service</address>
				<address>IRTM - BCT</address>
				<address>755  Parfet St. Suite #250</address>
				<city>Lakeood</city>
				<state>Colorado</state>
				<postal>80215</postal>
				<country>USA</country>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>303-275-2348</cntvoice>
			<cntemail>fwsgis@fws.gov</cntemail>
		</cntinfo>
	</ptcontac>
	<datacred>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service</datacred>
	<procdate>20091909</procdate>
	<procstep>
		<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
		<srcused></srcused>
		<procdate>20090819</procdate>
		<proctime>10262000</proctime>
	</procstep>
	<cntvoice>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address</cntvoice>
	<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
	<distliab>Although this data set has been processed successfully by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service using the best available information, no warranty, expressed or implied, is made regarding the accuracy or utility of the data on any other system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data. The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained in.</distliab>
	<stdorder>
		<digform>
			<digtinfo>
				<formname>GIS Data</formname>
			</digtinfo>
			<digtopt>
				<onlinopt>
					<computer>
						<networka>
							<networkr></networkr>
						</networka>
					</computer>
				</onlinopt>
			</digtopt>
		</digform>
		<fees>None</fees>
	</stdorder>
	<lineage></lineage>
	<mdLang>
		<languageCode value="eng"></languageCode>
		<countryCode value="USA"></countryCode>
	</mdLang>
	<mdChar>
		<CharSetCd value="004"></CharSetCd>
	</mdChar>
	<mdHrLv>
		<ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd>
	</mdHrLv>
	<mdContact>
		<rpOrgName>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service (USFWS),HQ, IRTM, BDSS</rpOrgName>
		<rpPosName>National GIS Coordinator</rpPosName>
		<rpCntInfo>
			<cntPhone>
				<voiceNum>303-275-2348</voiceNum>
			</cntPhone>
			<cntAddress addressType="postal">
				<delPoint>U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service</delPoint>
				<delPoint>IRTM - BCT</delPoint>
				<delPoint>755 Parfet St. Suite #250</delPoint>
				<city>Lakewood</city>
				<adminArea>Colorado</adminArea>
				<postCode>80215</postCode>
				<country>US</country>
				<eMailAdd>fwsgis@fws.gov</eMailAdd>
			</cntAddress>
		</rpCntInfo>
		<role>
			<RoleCd value="007"></RoleCd>
		</role>
	</mdContact>
	<mdDateSt>20121220</mdDateSt>
	<mdStanName>ArcGIS Metadata</mdStanName>
	<mdStanVer>1.0</mdStanVer>
	<distInfo>
		<distributor>
			<distorCont>
				<rpOrgName>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service (USFWS), HQ, IRTM, BDSS</rpOrgName>
				<rpCntInfo>
					<cntPhone>
						<voiceNum>303-275-2348</voiceNum>
					</cntPhone>
					<cntAddress addressType="postal">
						<delPoint>U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service</delPoint>
						<delPoint>755 Parfet St. Suite #250</delPoint>
						<city>Lakewood</city>
						<adminArea>CO</adminArea>
						<postCode>80215</postCode>
						<eMailAdd>fwsgis@fws.gov</eMailAdd>
					</cntAddress>
				</rpCntInfo>
				<role>
					<RoleCd value="005"></RoleCd>
				</role>
			</distorCont>
			<distorOrdPrc></distorOrdPrc>
			<distorTran>
				<transSize>5.089</transSize>
				<onLineSrc>
					<linkage></linkage>
				</onLineSrc>
			</distorTran>
		</distributor>
		<distTranOps>
			<onLineSrc>
				<linkage></linkage>
			</onLineSrc>
			<transSize>5.135</transSize>
		</distTranOps>
		<distFormat>
			<formatName>Shapefile</formatName>
		</distFormat>
	</distInfo>
	<dataIdInfo>
		<idCitation>
			<resTitle>FWS_LCC</resTitle>
			<date>
				<pubDate>2012-01-05</pubDate>
			</date>
			<citRespParty>
				<rpOrgName>U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service</rpOrgName>
				<rpCntInfo>
					<cntAddress>
						<delPoint>USA</delPoint>
					</cntAddress>
				</rpCntInfo>
				<role>
					<RoleCd value="010"></RoleCd>
				</role>
			</citRespParty>
			<citRespParty>
				<rpOrgName>US FWS</rpOrgName>
				<role>
					<RoleCd value="006"></RoleCd>
				</role>
			</citRespParty>
			<presForm>
				<PresFormCd value="005"></PresFormCd>
			</presForm>
			<presForm>
				<fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform>
			</presForm>
		</idCitation>
		<idAbs>Landscape conservation cooperatives (LCCs) are conservation-science partnerships between the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), and other federal agencies, states, tribes, NGOs, universities and stakeholders within a geographically defined area. They inform resource management decisions to address national-scale stressors-including habitat fragmentation, genetic isolation, spread of invasive species, and water scarcity-all of which are accelerated by climate change.</idAbs>
		<idPurp>LCCs provide scientific and technical support for conservation at "landscape" scales-the entire range of an identified priority species or groups of species. They support biological planning, conservation design, prioritizing and coordinating research, and designing species inventory and monitoring programs. LCCs also have a role in helping partners identify common goals and priorities to target the right science in the right places for efficient and effective conservation. By functioning as network of interdependent units rather than independent entities, LCC partnerships can accomplish a conservation mission no single agency or organization can accomplish alone.</idPurp>
		<idStatus>
			<ProgCd value="005"></ProgCd>
		</idStatus>
		<idPoC>
			<rpOrgName>US Fish and Wildlife Service</rpOrgName>
			<rpPosName>National GIS Coordinator</rpPosName>
			<rpCntInfo>
				<cntPhone>
					<voiceNum>303-275-2348</voiceNum>
				</cntPhone>
				<cntAddress addressType="both">
					<delPoint>755 Parfet St, Ste 250</delPoint>
					<city>Lakewood</city>
					<adminArea>CO</adminArea>
					<postCode>80215</postCode>
					<country>US</country>
					<eMailAdd>fwsgis@fws.gov</eMailAdd>
				</cntAddress>
			</rpCntInfo>
			<role>
				<RoleCd value="007"></RoleCd>
			</role>
		</idPoC>
		<resMaint>
			<maintFreq>
				<MaintFreqCd value="009"></MaintFreqCd>
			</maintFreq>
		</resMaint>
		<themeKeys>
			<keyword>landscape conservation cooperatives</keyword>
			<keyword>fish and wildlife service</keyword>
			<keyword>partnerships</keyword>
			<keyword>conservation</keyword>
			<keyword>LCC</keyword>
		</themeKeys>
		<searchKeys>
			<keyword>landscape conservation cooperatives</keyword>
			<keyword>fish and wildlife service</keyword>
			<keyword>partnerships</keyword>
			<keyword>conservation</keyword>
		</searchKeys>
		<resConst>
			<Consts>
				<useLimit>Inherent in any data set used to develop graphical representations, are limitations of accuracy as determined by, among others, the source, scale and resolution of the data. While the USFWS makes every effort to represent the data as completely and accurately as possible (given existing time and resource constraints), the USFWS gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. In addition, the USFWS shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained in. Graphical representations provided by the use of this data do not represent a legal description of any kind.</useLimit>
			</Consts>
		</resConst>
		<spatRpType>
			<SpatRepTypCd value="001"></SpatRepTypCd>
		</spatRpType>
		<dataLang>
			<languageCode value="eng"></languageCode>
			<countryCode value="USA"></countryCode>
		</dataLang>
		<envirDesc>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.1.1.3143</envirDesc>
		<dataExt>
			<geoEle>
				<GeoBndBox>
					<westBL>-180</westBL>
					<eastBL>180</eastBL>
					<southBL>-15.422167</southBL>
					<northBL>83.148084</northBL>
				</GeoBndBox>
			</geoEle>
		</dataExt>
		<dataExt>
			<exDesc>publication date</exDesc>
			<tempEle>
				<TempExtent>
					<exTemp>
						<TM_Instant>
							<tmPosition time="unknown">2012-01-05</tmPosition>
						</TM_Instant>
					</exTemp>
				</TempExtent>
			</tempEle>
			<geoEle></geoEle>
		</dataExt>
		<suppInfo>For further information go to http://www.fws.gov/science/shc/lcc.html Collectively, LCCs will comprise a seamless national network supporting landscapes capable of sustaining abundant, diverse and healthy populations of fish, wildlife and plants. They will provide a strong link between science and conservation delivery without duplicating existing partnerships or creating burdensome and unnecessary bureaucracy. Science-based recommendations and decision-support tools produced by LCCs will be readily transferable to field offices that implement on-the-ground actions. Rather than create a new conservation infrastructure from the ground up, LCCs build upon explicit biological management priorities and objectives, and science available from existing partnerships, such as fish habitat partnerships, migratory bird joint ventures and flyway councils, as well as species- and geographic-based partnerships. LCCs support adaptive resource management by evaluating implementation of conservation strategies, maintaining and sharing information and data, and improving products as new information becomes available. Shared data platforms serve multiple purposes, including the collaborative development of population/habitat models under alternative climate scenarios to inform spatially explicit decision support for all partners. Decision-support systems and products developed by LCCs not only help determine the most effective conservation actions to support shared priorities, but also provide tools to compare and contrast the implications of management alternatives. In the face of accelerated climate change and other 21st-century conservation challenges, LCCs will regularly evaluate the effectiveness of scientific information and conservation actions and support necessary adjustments as new information becomes available. This iterative process of information sharing will help scientists and resource managers deal with uncertainties on the landscape and provide tools to compare and contrast the implications of management alternatives. LCCs were created from Geographic Areas. See http://www.fws.gov/science/shc/index.html for further information. This layer was created through a union of the Bird Conservation Region (BCR) layer and the Freshwater Ecoregions layer (FEOW). The purpose of this union was to retrieve some of the linework and attributes from the FEOW layer. Some linework from the FEOW layer was used to split some BCRs in order to accommodate high priority aquatic areas. It was also decided to union in the "Mid Atlantic" Hydrographic Unit Code (HUC) Region (Level 2) into this dataset so we could use the actual topographic boundary between the Mid-Atlantic Region (including the James and Chesapeake) from the South-Atlantic Gulf Region (including the Chowan-Roanoake) to split the Atlantic coast area. This was used instead of the FEOW boundary in this area because it diverged from the topographic boundary. After the edits were made by the mapping sub-group, this layer had the multi-part to single-part tool run on it and all polygons that had a BCR = 0 were deleted. These polygons were either the sliver polygons that were created where the FEOW and the BCR coast lines differed or FEOW polygons from areas not in North America. This was done to clean up the dataset. It also allowed the Team to select and classify the many small island polygons along the coast that were accidentally dropped out during the quick group editing process. “Gulf Coast Prairie” was updated to extend further east, Sept. 16, 2009. Names for several geographic areas were changed. “Insular Pacific-Hawaii” became “Pacific Islands,”” Northern Great Plains” became “Plains and Prairie Potholes,”” Northern Rockies” became “Great Northern” to comply more closely with LCC names. Changed Oct 7, 2009. The Geographic Area "South Pacific" was changed to "California"; "Northern Interior Forest" was changed to "Northwestern Interior Forest" and "Northern Atlantic" was changed to "North Atlantic". The “Pacific Islands” area was enlarged to include the new area identified by the regional climate change group. All edits were vetted through the FWS National Climate Team. November 12, 2009. Changes in geographic area names have been approved by LCC Coordinators Teresa Woods (“Eastern Tallgrass Prairie” is now “Eastern Tallgrass Prairie and Big Rivers”), Bob Ford (“South Florida” is now “Peninsular Florida”), Kathy Granillo (“Southern Great Plains” is now “Great Plains”) and Laverne Smith (“Northern Alaska” is now “Arctic”) on December 7, 2009. "Gulf Coast Plain and Ozarks" Geographic Area/LCC name changed to "Gulf Coastal Plains and Ozarks" (authorized by R4 Bill Uihlein - Interim Coordinator), "Arctic Plains and Mountains" Geographic Area name/LCC changed to "Arctic" (authorized by Phillip Martin - R7 Interim Coordinator), Dec 23, 2009. Data correction - added “Great Lakes” area to “Upper Midwest and Great Lakes” geographic area (authorized by Dan Ash (Science Advisor), John Wenburg (Acting Deputy Science Advisor) and Teresa Woods (R3 Interim LCC Coordinator)), Jan 6, 2010. Changed “Arctic” LCC to include entire Arctic Geographic Area (authorized by LaVerne Smith (R7 Science Applications ARD), Phillip Martin (R7 Interim LCC Coordinator), and John Wenburg (Acting Deputy Science Advisor)). Removed “Upper Midwest and Great Lakes” LCC. Combined Geographic Areas and LCC dataset into one layer of information and removed references to those LCCs that have FWS operational plans to make the datasets more generic and to conform to the current maps on the FWS and DOI websites (authorized by Chris Lett, John Wenburg, and David Eisenhauer, April 15, 2010.) Caribbean LCC added December 18, 2011, compiled from United Stated Exclusive Economic Zone around Puerto Rico, approved by Doug Austen, National LCC Coordinator, on December 14, 2011.</suppInfo>
		<dataExt>
			<geoEle>
				<GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search">
					<exTypeCode>1</exTypeCode>
					<westBL>-180.000000</westBL>
					<eastBL>180.000000</eastBL>
					<northBL>83.148084</northBL>
					<southBL>-15.422167</southBL>
				</GeoBndBox>
			</geoEle>
		</dataExt>
	</dataIdInfo>
	<dqInfo>
		<dqScope>
			<scpLvl>
				<ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd>
			</scpLvl>
		</dqScope>
		<report type="DQConcConsis">
			<measDesc>Not Available</measDesc>
		</report>
		<report type="DQCompOm">
			<measDesc>Not Available</measDesc>
		</report>
		<report type="DQQuanAttAcc">
			<measDesc>Not available</measDesc>
		</report>
		<report type="DQAbsExtPosAcc" dimension="horizontal">
			<measDesc>Not Available</measDesc>
		</report>
	</dqInfo>
	<mdHrLvName>dataset</mdHrLvName>
	<refSysInfo>
		<RefSystem>
			<refSysID>
				<identCode code="4326"></identCode>
				<idCodeSpace>EPSG</idCodeSpace>
				<idVersion>7.11.2</idVersion>
			</refSysID>
		</RefSystem>
	</refSysInfo>
	<spatRepInfo>
		<VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="lcc"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">0</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20131204</CreaDate><CreaTime>13505400</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.2\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Editing Tools.tbx\Generalize" Date="20141017" Time="143419">Generalize LCC "1 Kilometers"</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.3\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\RepairGeometry" Date="20150317" Time="105109">RepairGeometry LCC KEEP_NULL</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.4\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Merge" Date="20160229" Time="133139">Merge 'AOI_LCC_Lambert selection' C:\testclip\lcc.shp "area_names "area_names" true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,AOI_LCC_Lambert selection,area_names,-1,-1;Area_Num "Area_Num" true true false 4 Short 0 4 ,First,#,AOI_LCC_Lambert selection,Area_Num,-1,-1"</Process></lineage><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">lcc</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><itemSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</itemSize><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\MMITCHELL-PC\C$\testclip\lcc.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: m (1.000000)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">Lambert_Conformal_Conic</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.4'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;Lambert_Conformal_Conic&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_WGS_1984&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_WGS_1984&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;WGS_1984&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Lambert_Conformal_Conic&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,5632642.22547],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,4612545.65137],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-107.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_1&amp;quot;,50.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_2&amp;quot;,50.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Scale_Factor&amp;quot;,1.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,50.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;m&amp;quot;,1.0]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-30425900&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-26083600&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;124896858.78579408&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef></DataProperties><SyncDate>20160229</SyncDate><SyncTime>13313900</SyncTime><ModDate>20160229</ModDate><ModTime>13313900</ModTime></Esri></metadata>
